National Congress of Neighborhood Women Records, 1974-1999
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION 1974-1996
  - National committee: memoranda, minutes, reports, and printed material, 1976-79 (Box 4, Folder 16-18)
  - Miscellaneous task forces: list, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - National meetings and conferences
    [See also Corporate Board; National Steering Committee, National Planning Committee; SERIES II. PROGRAMS - Leadership-National Training]
    - Planning meeting (founding), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      [See also SERIES V. AUDIOVISUAL - videotapes]
    - "Neighborhood Women: A Call to Action," 1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - "NCNW: A Working Conference," 1978 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - National planning conferences, 1979-80 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - National convention, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Regional conference, Las Vegas, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - National planning conference, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - National planning meetings, 1987-88 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Local - Neighborhood Women of Williamsburg/Greenpoint (NWWG)
    - General: brochure, and letterhead, letter of agreement with NCNW, 1986, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Chronological files
      - 1987-88 (Box 5, Folder 7-13)
      - 1989-92 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Board of Directors
      - General, 1989-94, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Minutes and agendas, 1991, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - By-laws: drafts and final version, 1988, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Consultants
      - Community Resource Exchange, 1992-96 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Jan Peterson, 1990-91, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Contract contacts: lists and correspondence, 1989-93 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Financial, 1989-95, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Mailing lists, 1988-94, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Local Advisory Board
      - General, 1981-87, undated (Box 6, Folder 11-13)
      - Membership list, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Task Forces, 1983-85, undated (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
    - Local Planning Committee, 1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Neighborhood Women's Renaissance, 1990-93, undated (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
      [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS - Housing and tenants]
    - Policies and procedures, 1983, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Publicity contacts, 1986, 1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Staff, circa 1986-92, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Training, Institute of Cultural Affairs, 1984, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Programs
      [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS]
      - General, 1989-94, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Job Training Partnership Act (JTPA) Program, 1989-94 (Box 7, Folder 9-14)
      - WEEA: application, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Resources: lists, 1986-92, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
      [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Resource Center]
    - Miscellaneous, 1983-93, undated
      - Incoming correspondence and printed material, 1984-94, undated (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
      - Interviews with NWWG staff by Mary Belenky: transcript, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Unidentified notes, 1983-94, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Staff
    - Lists and biographical profiles (Box 8, Folder 6-9)
    - Correspondence and memoranda: general, 1978-88 undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
      [See also General chronological file]
    - Logs and reports, 1979-80 (Box 8, Folder 11-19)
    - Meetings
      - Administrative, 1977-87, undated (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
      - Coordinators, 1978-80 (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
      - General assembly, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Staff meetings, 1975-88, undated (Box 9, Folder 9-17)
      - Staff retreats, 1976-87 (Box 9, Folder 18-22)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Office procedures, 1980-86 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Personnel
      - Job descriptions (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Personnel policies: minutes, memoranda, drafts, notes, and printed material (Box 10, Folder 2-11)
        [See also National Steering Committee]
      - Salaries and benefits (Box 10, Folder 12-15)
    - Staff newsletter (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Staff support group (Box 11, Folder 2)
      [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Leadership-Support groups]
    - Training and development workshops (Box 11, Folder 3-7)
  - Individuals
    - Amigo, Lanny (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Austermiller, Judy (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Belenky, Mary (Box 11, Folder 10)
      [See also Local-Miscellaneous for Interviews with NWWG staff by Mary Belenky]
    - Burns, Lisel (Leadership Coordinator)
      - Subject files
        - Baltimore consultation (Box 11, Folder 11)
        - "Bringing HABITAT Home" campaign (Box 11, Folder 12)
        - Cambridge, MA (Box 11, Folder 13)
        - Chicago WES (Women for Economic Security) Conference (Box 11, Folder 14)
        - Cirillo, Marie (Box 11, Folder 15)
        - Citiworks meeting (Box 11, Folder 16)
        - Dissertation proposal (Box 11, Folder 17)
        - ECCO-Training resources (Box 11, Folder 18)
        - Florida (Box 11, Folder 19)
        - Ford project, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 20)
        - Forums Set 1 1989-National Report (Box 11, Folder 21)
        - Fundraisers (Box 11, Folder 22)
        - Grailville (Box 11, Folder 23)
        - HERG overview (Box 11, Folder 24)
        - H.O.M.E. (Box 11, Folder 25)
        - Housing Options for Women (conference) (Box 11, Folder 26-27)
          [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Housing]
        - Institute for Living Democracy (Box 11, Folder 28)
        - International
          - Brooklyn Women's Speakout (Box 12, Folder 1)
          - Forging a National Alliance with International Linkages (Box 12, Folder 2)
          - Grameen Bank-USA-"Reciprocal Responsibility" (Box 12, Folder 3)
          - GROOTS - Owen (Box 12, Folder 4)
          - In Another Way (Box 12, Folder 5)
          - ICA materials (Box 12, Folder 6)
          - ICA Portugal trip- 1991 (Box 12, Folder 7)
          - Ied Guinee (Box 12, Folder 8)
          - RREMA GOPALAN (Box 12, Folder 9)
          - Yolaine Armand-Haiti (Box 12, Folder 10)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 11)
        - Leadership training
          [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Leadership]
          - General: correspondence, meetings, and notes (Box 12, Folder 12-16)
          - Training materials (Box 12, Folder 17-23)
          - Training sessions, 1988-96 (Box 13, Folder 1-8)
          - Regional forums (Box 13, Folder 9-18)
        - Learning Alliance Forum (Box 14, Folder 1)
        - McLaughlin, Peggy (Box 14, Folder 2)
        - Martin, Terrence (Box 14, Folder 3)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 4-6)
        - Ms. Foundation (Box 14, Folder 7)
        - NCNW
          - Events (Box 14, Folder 8)
          - National Planning Committee (Box 14, Folder 9)
          - Strategic plan (Box 14, Folder 10)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 11)
        - Northwest-Colorado (Box 14, Folder 12)
        - Staff meeting (Box 14, Folder 13)
        - Statistics USA, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 14)
        - Stoneman, Dorothy (Box 14, Folder 15)
        - Stony Pt. Institute Planning Retreat, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 16)
        - Unitarian Universalism Partners (Box 14, Folder 17)
        - Washington Delegates Meeting, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 18)
        - Woman/Housing Conference (Box 14, Folder 19)
        - Women for Economic Security (Box 14, Folder 20)
        - Women's Community Development Institute (Box 14, Folder 21)
        - Women's International Day Platform (Box 14, Folder 22)
        - Woodland County Land Trust (Box 14, Folder 23)
        - Youthbuild Coalition (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Charlop, Simone (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Cincotta, Gail (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Cirillo, Marie (Box 15, Folder 3-7)
    - Cooper, Lois (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Edwards, Rita Morgan (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Fava, Maria (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Feit, Rona (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Fisher, Sally (Box 15, Folder 12-16)
    - Frazier, Louise (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Gilkey, Bertha (Box 15, Folder 18-20)
      [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Housing and tenants]
    - Giordano, Ann (Box 15, Folder 21-24)
    - Grey, Linda (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Haywoode, Terry (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Jonda, Judy (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Jones¸Evelyn (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Lowe, Sandy (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Morelli, Gina (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Moresco, Ginger (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Mufson, Susan (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Noschese, Christine, Executive Director, 1977-79
      [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Resource Center-Documentaries]
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - Oct 1974 - June 1978 (Box 16, Folder 10-19)
          - July 1978 - May 1980 (Box 17, Folder 1-13)
        - Fundraising (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
      - Subject files
        - Channel 13 (Box 18, Folder 1)
        - Ethnicity
          - "Ethnicity and the Media" by C. Noschese (Box 18, Folder 2)
          - Conference on the Educational and Occupational Needs of White Ethnic Women (Box 18, Folder 3)
          - Ethnic Studies Program (Box 18, Folder 4)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 5)
        - Family Protection Agenda (Box 18, Folder 6)
        - "Goat Story" by C. Noschese (Box 18, Folder 7)
        - Interview with C. Noschese: transcript, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 8)
        - Italian-American Conference (Box 18, Folder 9)
        - Neighborhood Foundation (Box 18, Folder 10)
        - Newspaper (Box 18, Folder 11)
        - Miscellaneous: notes (Box 18, Folder 12-14)
    - Pennington, Ashley (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Peterson, Jan, Executive Director, 1975-77; 1980-
      - Biographical information (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - Chronological file
        [See also Central chronological file and SERIES II. PROGRAMS-International]
        - 1976 - Dec 1980 (Box 18, Folder 17-21)
        - undated (circa 1980) - Sep 1981 (Box 19, Folder 1-8)
        - undated (circa 1981)- 1982 (Box 20, Folder 1-9)
        - Jan 1983-14 Aug 1983 (Box 21, Folder 1-9)
        - 15 Aug 1983-18 Jan 1987 (Box 22, Folder 1-8)
        - 19 Jan 1987 - Oct 1990 (Box 23, Folder 1-9)
          (Jul 1987 - May 1989 missing)
      - Reports, 1980-86 (Box 24, Folder 1-4)
        [See also SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION-General and National Corporate Board-Reports]
      - Subjects
        [See also SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION-Subjects]
        - ACTION (Box 24, Folder 5)
        - Agenda for Dialogues (Box 24, Folder 6)
        - Battered women (Box 24, Folder 7)
        - Big Business Coalition (Box 24, Folder 8)
        - Bills - Vienna (Box 24, Folder 9)
        - Board and NSC (Box 24, Folder 10)
        - Calendar, 1984-85 (Box 24, Folder 11)
        - Co-host - National Conference on Women and Housing (Box 24, Folder 12)
        - Columbia University (Box 24, Folder 13)
        - Community Gospel Church (Box 24, Folder 14)
        - Conselyea St. Block Association (Box 24, Folder 15)
        - Consultants (Box 24, Folder 16)
        - Emergency work (Box 24, Folder 17)
        - FYI (Box 24, Folder 18)
        - Greenpoint Hospital (Box 24, Folder 19)
        - Group dynamics course (Box 24, Folder 20)
        - Human Resources Administration (H.R.A.) (Box 24, Folder 21-22)
        - ICA (Box 24, Folder 23)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 1-4)
        - N.Y.C. Housing Authority (Box 25, Folder 5)
        - N.Y. State - Gail Shaffer (Box 25, Folder 6)
        - Needs assessments (Box 25, Folder 7)
        - Personal (Box 25, Folder 8-9)
        - Policy Advisory Council (Box 25, Folder 10)
        - Program goals - National (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Program planning (Box 25, Folder 12)
        - Proposal (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - Receipts/records (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - Reports of staff (Box 25, Folder 15)
        - Speaking engagements, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 16)
        - Testimony - J.P. legal correspondence (Box 25, Folder 17)
        - Travel arrangements (Box 25, Folder 18)
        - U.S. Department of Labor (Box 25, Folder 19)
        - Warwick Retreat (Box 25, Folder 20)
        - "Women on the Move in Neighborhoods" (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Quinn, Alice, co-Executive Director, 1983-85
      - Chronological file
        - 1977 - Apr 1983 (Box 25, Folder 22-24)
        - May 1983 - Jul 1984 (Box 26, Folder 1-3)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Reed, Rosemarie (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Scanlon, Laura (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Schilen, Sandy (Box 26, Folder 7-9)
    - Springer, Edith (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Staton, Rebecca (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Strickland, Sharon (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Sutton, Crystal Lee (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Williams, Dorothy (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Wooten, Wanda (Box 27, Folder 1-5)
  - Building
    - General (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Engineer's report, 1981-83 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - NY State Division of Housing and Urban Renewal, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Heat policy/controversy, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 9-11)
    - Telephones, 1978-79, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Energy grants, 1988-90 (Box 27, Folder 13-14)
    - Energy grants, 1988-90 (continued) (Box 28, Folder 1-5)
  - Public relations
    [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Resource Center and publicity under specific programs]
    - Administration: correspondence and report, 1977-81 (Box 28, Folder 6-9)
    - Publicity
      - Brochures and flyers (Box 28, Folder 10-11)
      - Articles (Box 28, Folder 12)
        [See SERIES II. PROGRAMS - Resource Center - NCNW; also subject files under specific programs; and OVERSIZED MATERIAL]
      - Press releases (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Radio (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - General descriptions of NCNW, 1975-88, undated (Box 28, Folder 15-19)
    - Publications
      - Newsletters (incomplete run)
        [See also OVERSIZED MATERIAL]
        - General: correspondence, meetings, proposals, and reports, 1979-86 (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
        - National Congress of Neighborhood Women Quarterly, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - Neighborhood Woman, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 5)
        - Neighborhood Women, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 6)
        - Neighborhood Women Network News, 1980-81 (Box 29, Folder 7-9)
        - National Congress of Neighborhood Women Newsletter, 1983, 1985-86 (Box 29, Folder 10)
        - Neighborhood Woman, 1990-91, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 11)
        - Miscellaneous material for newsletters: clippings, artwork, drafts, and notes (Box 29, Folder 12-17)
      - Miscellaneous publications
        - Holiday letter, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 18)
        - "Remember Williamsburg-Greenpoint" (Box 29, Folder 19)
        - Training Sourcebook: flyer (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Mailing lists (Box 29, Folder 21-30)
  - Membership
    [See also SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS]
    - Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Information packet and blank membership forms (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Lists (Box 30, Folder 3-5)
    - Membership forms, completed (Box 30, Folder 6-17)
    - Miscellaneous: notes and receipts (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Central chronological file
    [See also Local; Individuals; and SERIES II. PROGRAMS-International]
    - 1973 - Jun 1980 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Jun 1980 - Jan 1984 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Feb - Oct 1984 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - Nov 1984-11 Apr 1986 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - 18 Apr - Aug 1986 (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - Sep - Nov 1986 (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - Dec 1986-19 Feb 1987 (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - 20 Feb-8 Mar 1987 (Box 30, Folder 38)
    - 9 Apr - May 1987 (Box 30, Folder 39)
    - Jun 1987 - May 1989 (Box 30, Folder 40)
    - Jun - Jul 1989, undated (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
  - General correspondence, 1975-87, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 3-12)
  - Subjects
    - Advocacy (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Assemblymen (Box 42, Folder 2-3)
    - Board of Education (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Breakfast meetings (Box 42, Folder 5-6)
    - Brooklyn Legal Services (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Brooklyn Union Gas Company (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Bulk mailing (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Calendars (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Certificates (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Church (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Church women luncheon (Box 42, Folder 13-16)
    - Community creativity (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - Community organizations (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - CONEXUS (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - Corporation proposal (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - Directions to NCNW (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - Documentation (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - Domestic/family violence (Box 42, Folder 23-25)
    - Eastern district (Box 42, Folder 26)
    - "ERA and Beyond" (Box 42, Folder 27)
    - Form letters (Box 42, Folder 28-29)
    - Greenpoint YMCA (Box 42, Folder 30)
    - Information requests (Box 42, Folder 31)
    - Interns (Box 42, Folder 32)
    - Italian-American Civil Rights League (Box 42, Folder 33)
    - J.P. Stevens (Box 42, Folder 34)
    - Koch goals (Box 42, Folder 35)
    - Local community issues (Box 42, Folder 36)
    - Local politicians (Box 42, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 42, Folder 38-40)
    - Miscellaneous meetings (Box 42, Folder 41)
    - National (Box 42, Folder 42)
    - National conference: Women organizers' discussion group, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - National Italian-American Foundation (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - National organizing letters (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - National women leaders (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Needs assessment questionnaire (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Neighborhood development (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - New York City (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - New York State (Box 43, Folder 8-18)
    - "Next Step" awards (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - "Outstationed letters" (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Policy Plus decision making (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Political (Box 43, Folder 22-25)
    - Politician's letters (Box 43, Folder 26)
    - Regional offices (Box 43, Folder 27)
    - Rutgers University (Box 43, Folder 28)
    - School Board Election (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - School Settlement Association (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Small business development (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Smith College (Archives list) (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Sperry (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Thank you letters (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Department of Labor (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - U.S. Department of Labor - National Women's Bureau (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - United States Mission to the United Nations (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - White House (Box 44, Folder 10-11)
    - Williamsburg/Greenpoint: statistics and information (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Williamsburg/Greenpoint Planning Committee (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Women in Politics (L.A.B. Task Force) (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Women torture victims (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Women's delegation (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Development
    [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS for funding of specific projects]
    - General
      - Correspondence and memoranda (Box 45, Folder 1-4)
      - Fundraising (Box 45, Folder 5-8)
      - Reports, circa 1977-86 (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - Funding history: lists of funding sources, 1975-88 (Box 45, Folder 10-14)
      - Funding resources: lists and printed material (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Proposals
      - Guidelines (Box 45, Folder 16)
      - Profiles for rejected proposals (Box 45, Folder 17-18)
    - General funding proposals
      - 1977-78 (Box 45, Folder 19-21)
      - 1979-81 (Box 46, Folder 1-19)
      - 1982-86, undated (Box 47, Folder 1-10)
    - Attachments for proposals: organization and program descriptions, histories, reports, publicity, and statistics (Box 47, Folder 11-18)
      [See also Public relations- General descriptions of NCNW]
  - Funding agencies
    - Action (Box 47, Folder 19-21)
    - ACLU (Box 48, Folder 1)
      [See also Housing Conference and NY DOE - CETA]
    - Apple Computer, Inc. (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Aspen Institute (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Association for Community Based Education (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Avon (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - BECA (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Board of Global Ministries (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Campaign for Human Development (Box 48, Folder 8-13)
    - Carnegie Foundation (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - CHAKRA Systems (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Chemical Bank (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Church Women United (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - City Project (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Community Service Society (Box 48, Folder 19-25)
    - Consumer Farmers Foundation (Box 48, Folder 26)
    - Control Data Corporation (Box 48, Folder 27)
    - Coro Foundation (Box 48, Folder 28)
    - Dorf and Stanton Foundation (Box 48, Folder 29)
    - Eastman Foundation (Box 48, Folder 30)
    - Edna McConnell Clark Foundation (Box 48, Folder 31)
    - Eisenhower Foundation for the Prevention of Violence (Box 48, Folder 32)
    - Enterprise Foundation (Box 48, Folder 33)
    - Equitable Foundation (Box 48, Folder 34)
    - Environmental Education Project (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Film Fund (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 49, Folder 3-4)
    - Foundation Center (Box 49, Folder 5-6)
    - Fund for Human Dignity (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Fund for the City of New York (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education (FIPSE) (Box 49, Folder 9-14)
    - Fund for the Improvement (continued) (Box 50, Folder 1-4)
    - Gannett Foundation (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - German Marshall Fund (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Guggenheim Foundation (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Hearst Foundation (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Housing and Urban Development (HUD) (Box 50, Folder 9-11)
    - Irvine Foundation (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - J.M. Kaplan Foundation (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Johnson Foundation (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Joint Foundation (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Joyce Mertz-Gilmore Foundation (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Levi Strauss (Box 50, Folder 17-18)
    - Lillia Babbitt Hyde Foundation (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Metropolitan Life (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Miller, Maya (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Morris Goldseker Foundation of Maryland, Inc. (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - Ms. Foundation for Women (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - National Child Labor Committee (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - National Community Funds (Box 50, Folder 25)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - National Women's Education Fund (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - New Jersey (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - New York City-Community Development Agency (Box 51, Folder 4-23)
      [See also SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS-Williamsburg/Greenpoint Community Planning Board]
    - New York City-Community Services Administration (Box 52, Folder 1-16)
      [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Community and economic development; Resource Center; and SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS-Center for Community Change]
    - New York City-Department of Employment-Comprehensive Employment Training Act (CETA)
      [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Employment]
      - General
        - Correspondence
          - 1977-81 (Box 52, Folder 17-19)
          - 1982-83, undated (Box 53, Folder 1)
        - Contract, 1978 (Box 53, Folder 2)
        - Proposals and applications (Box 53, Folder 3-7)
        - Appeals, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 8)
        - Meetings
          - Community Council of Greater New York: correspondence, meetings, notes, and printed material, 1977-82, undated (Box 53, Folder 9-10)
          - NCNW task force on CETA legislation: memorandum, 1978 (Box 53, Folder 11)
          - Task Force on CETA-CBO Coalition Building, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 12)
          - Conference on CBO's and CETA, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 13)
        - Reports (Box 53, Folder 13-14)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 54, Folder 1-7)
      - Legal cases
        - New York City Unemployment and Welfare Council v. The NCNW and Project Open Doors, 1978-79 (Box 54, Folder 8)
        - NCNW v. City of New York, 1979-80
          [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Employment-Project Open Doors]
          - Correspondence (Box 54, Folder 9-10)
          - Court documents, 1980-81 (Box 55, Folder 1-8)
          - Transcripts, 1979-80 (Box 55, Folder 9-10)
          - Publicity, 1975-80, undated (Box 55, Folder 11)
          - Letters requesting support, 1979-81 (Box 55, Folder 12)